[
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can read and render HTML web pages",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) web browsers can read and render HTML web pages.",
    "options": [
      "Server",
      "head Tak",
      "web browser",
      "empty"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the range of byte data types in JavaScript.",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) the range of byte data type is - 128 to 127.",
    "options": [
      "-10 to 9",
      "- 128 to 127",
      "-32768 to 32767",
      "-2147483648 to 2147483647"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Among the following operators identify the one which is used to allocate memory to array variables in JavaScript.",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) new Is used to allocate memory to array variables in JavaScript.",
    "options": [
      "new",
      "new malloc",
      "alloc",
      "malloc"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The latest HTML standard is",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) The latest HTML standard is HTML 5.0",
    "options": [
      "HTML 4.0",
      "HTML 5.0",
      "XML",
      "SGML"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Why were cookies designed?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) Cookies were designed for server-side programming.",
    "options": [
      "for server-side programming",
      "For client-side programming",
      "both a and b",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What are variables used in JavaScript programs",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) Variables are used to store numbers, dates, and other values.",
    "options": [
      "Varying randomly",
      "Storing numbers, dates, and other values",
      "Used as header files",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Simple network management protocol uses which of the following port number",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) simple network management protocol uses port number 161.",
    "options": [
      "164",
      "163",
      "160",
      "161"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the incorrect HTML tag among the following",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) < list>  is in correct HTML tag among the following.",
    "options": [
      "< input>",
      "<select>",
      "< list>",
      "< textarea>"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Full form of W3C is _____________",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) W3C stands for World Wide Web consortium.",
    "options": [
      "World Wide Websites community",
      "World Wide Web community",
      "World Wide Websites consortium",
      "World Wide Web consortium"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the empty or void element in HTML.",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) <br> Is the empty or void element in HTML",
    "options": [
      "<sup>",
      "<br>",
      "<p>",
      "< abbr>"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following attribute is used for merging two or more adjacent columns?",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) COLSPAN Is used for merging two or more adjacent columns.",
    "options": [
      "ROWSPAN",
      "CELLSPACING",
      "COLSPAN",
      "CELLPADDING"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is used to transmit information on the world wide web?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) HTTP Is used to transmit information on the world wide web.",
    "options": [
      "HPPT",
      "HTTP",
      "HTTTP",
      "HTPP"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "A website is a _______  cookie.",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) a website is a transient cookie.",
    "options": [
      "volatile",
      "transient",
      "in transient",
      "non-volatile"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Among which of the following is HTML a subset.",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) HTML  it is a subset of SGML.",
    "options": [
      "SGMD",
      "SGMT",
      "SGML",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "When is the body tag used?",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) Body tag is used after the HEAD tag.",
    "options": [
      "after FORM tag",
      "after Title tag",
      "after EM tag",
      "after HEAD tag"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "To establish the base URL which of the following is used?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) To establish the base URL BASE element is used.",
    "options": [
      "BASE element",
      "HEAD element",
      "both a and b",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "On which model is www based upon",
    "answer": "Explanation: A)  www is based upon client-server.",
    "options": [
      "client-server",
      "local server",
      "3 tier",
      "none of this"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the container among the following",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) Both <body> and <select> containers.",
    "options": [
      "< body>",
      "< select>",
      "< input>",
      "both a and b"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following attribute defines the relationship between the current document and  URL?",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) REL defines the relationship between the current document and HREF’ed URL.",
    "options": [
      "URL",
      "REV",
      "REL",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The MIME text file is saved with which of the following extension",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) MIME text file is saved with HTML extension.",
    "options": [
      "THM extension",
      "HTML extension",
      "HTM extension",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is XPATH used?",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) XPATH is used to address the document by specifying a location path",
    "options": [
      "To address the server",
      "to store the IP address of this server",
      "to address the document by specifying a location path",
      "none"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identified among the following which creates push button",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) RESET  is used to create a push-button.",
    "options": [
      "RESET",
      "CHECK BOX",
      "INPUT",
      "RADIO"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "How many sizes of headers are available in HTML by default?",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) 6 headers are available in HTML by default ranging from h1 to h6.",
    "options": [
      "5",
      "1",
      "3",
      "6"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the types of lists available in HTML?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) The lists available in HTML are Ordered and Unordered List.",
    "options": [
      "Ordered, unordered lists",
      "Bulleted, numbered lists",
      "Named, Unnamed lists",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "HTML files are saved by default with the extension?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) HTML files are saved by the .html or .htm extension.",
    "options": [
      ".h",
      ".html",
      ".ht",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the effect of the \\<b> tag?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) It converts the text within it to a bold tag.",
    "options": [
      "It converts the text within it to a bold tag.",
      "It is used to write black-colored font",
      "It is used to change the font size.",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tags doesn’t require a closing tag?",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) Both the \\<hr> and the \\<br> tag doesn’t require a closing tag.",
    "options": [
      "\\<br>",
      "\\<hr>",
      "Both (a) and (b)",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the attributes used to change the size of an image?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) Width and Height attributes are used to change the size of an image.",
    "options": [
      "Big and Small",
      "Width and height",
      "Top and bottom",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which attribute is used to provide a unique name to an HTML element?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) An id is used to provide a unique name for an HTML element that can be used to identify it.",
    "options": [
      "id",
      "class",
      "type",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of the HTML style attribute?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A)  It is used to add styles to an HTML element.",
    "options": [
      "It is used to add styles to an HTML element.",
      "It is used to uniquely identify some specific styles of some elements.",
      "Both (a) and (b)",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which HTML element is used to define description data?",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) Description data is defined by <dd> tag.",
    "options": [
      "\\<li>",
      "\\<ol>",
      "\\<dd>",
      "\\<dl>"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following properties is used to change the font of text?",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) The font-family property is used to change text font in HTML.",
    "options": [
      "font-family",
      "font-size",
      "text-align",
      "None"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the correct option related to XML.",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) XML is a storage format but a textual storage format that can be called a language.",
    "options": [
      "It cannot be used as a database",
      "it can be used as a database",
      "it is a storage format but a textual storage format which can be called a language",
      "it is not a database, it is a language"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the map definition file generally stored?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) The map definition file is generally stored in CGI-BIN.",
    "options": [
      "RECYCLE BIN",
      "CGI-BIN",
      "BIN",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Document Object Model(DOM)?",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) DOM is a  parser.",
    "options": [
      "a coding style",
      "Specification",
      "a parser",
      "none"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the function in JavaScript which is used to send messages to users requesting for text input?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) prompt() it is used to send messages to users requesting text input.",
    "options": [
      "alert()",
      "prompt()",
      "display()",
      "getInput()"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the method which is used to specify a container's layout in JSP.",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) setLayout() Is used to specify a container's layout in JSP.",
    "options": [
      "setContainerLayout()",
      "Layout()",
      "setLayout()",
      "none"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "To get the current system date which of the following function is used in ASP?",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) Date() Is used to get the current system date.",
    "options": [
      "CurrentDate()",
      "getDate()",
      "Now()",
      "Date()"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "The full form of DOM is?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) DOM  stands for document object model.",
    "options": [
      "Document-oriented memory",
      "document object model",
      "document object memory",
      "none"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the total standard color names that HTML supports.",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) HTML supports a total of 140 standard color names.",
    "options": [
      "30",
      "70",
      "140",
      "120"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the tag used to give paragraph",
    "answer": "Explanation: A) <p> Is used to give paragraph.",
    "options": [
      "<p>",
      "<br>",
      "<marquee>",
      "< pre>"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the tag which is used to define a concept in HTML.",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) <def> is used to define a concept in HTML",
    "options": [
      "<p>",
      "<def>",
      "<marquee>",
      "< pre>"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the standard network protocol used to transfer computer files between a client and server on a computer network.",
    "answer": "Explanation: C) FTP is the standard protocol used to transfer computer files between the client and server in a computer network.",
    "options": [
      "Physical",
      "TCP/IP",
      "FTP",
      "Hyperlink"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose among the following, which is the most common internet protocol.",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) SMTP is the most commonly used internet protocol.",
    "options": [
      "PPP",
      "FTP",
      "TCP/IP",
      "SMTP"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Choose the port number of FTP.",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) The port number of FTP is 21",
    "options": [
      "23",
      "21",
      "110",
      "143"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "What does MIME stand for?",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) MIME stands for Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension.",
    "options": [
      "Multipurpose Internet Mail Extra",
      "Multi Internet Mail End",
      "Multipurpose Internet Mail Email",
      "Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensio"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is used to allocate and manage resources for a network?",
    "answer": "Explanation: B) Server is used to allocate and manage resources for a network.",
    "options": [
      "Bluetooth",
      "Server",
      "Node",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "done": false
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify among the following servers which allow LAN users to share data.",
    "answer": "Explanation: D) File server allows LAN users to share data.",
    "options": [
      "Communication server",
      "Point server",
      "Data server",
      "File server"
    ],
    "done": false
  }
]